Mark Thomas Calcagno

Address: 559 Victoria Ln, Wood Dale, IL. 60191

Phone Number: (224) 588 – 1304 Email: mcalcagn@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/mcalcagno47

Objective: After teaching math in the Chicago Public School system for 7 years, I discovered a love and aptitude for coding languages, specifically the logic of the back-end. After researching assorted avenues for learning, I applied and was accepted to Northwestern University's coding boot-camp, put on by Trilogy. For 6 months, I taught during the day and coded at night, learning every language and concept put in front of me. I'm a dedicated worker, a quick learner, and ready to add my experience and expertise to any team I work on.

Education Experience and Certification Area

Northwestern Bootcamp: attended from September 2022 to March 2023

Coding Certificate

Northeastern Illinois University: attended from August, 2009 to December, 2014

Bachelor's degree

Elementary Education Certificate, Middle Level Education Certificate

Coding Experience

Part time student, Northwestern Illinois University, Coding Boot Camp, September 2022 to March 2023

- Front-end and back-end web development training
- Coding languages learned but not limited to:
 - o HTML
 - o CSS
 - JavaScript
 - Node.is
 - o Express
 - o SOL
 - Model View Controllers
 - o API integration
 - o Progressive Web Applications
 - o MongoDB
 - React
 - o MERN
- Created web applications including, but not limited to:
 - Movie Review Website
 - https://so-bad-its-good.herokuapp.com/
 - Poker themed workout application
 - https://the-fighting-mongooses-official.github.io/Cards-Against-Apathy/
 - Social Network API creation
 - Database creation
 - o Interactive Ouiz
 - o Daily Calendar
 - Weather forecast
- Achieved a final grade of A

Teaching Experience

Middle School Math teacher, Peter Reinberg Elementary, Chicago Public Schools, August of 2015 to Present

- Description
 - Improved math MAP test scores among IEP and gen ed students.
 - Achieved growth in the 99th percentile nationally in the 2017-2018 and 2018-2019 school years.
 - In depth collaboration with Special Education teachers to ensure growth.
 - Created cohort to ensure clear communication between general education and special education teachers.
 - Created Mentorship Program for both new and experienced teachers recently hired at Reinberg Elementary.
 - Established avenues for parent communication that improved student performance.
 - Used online resources such as Google Classroom, Google Forms, Kahoot, and others to provide paperless assignments with immediate feedback for students including, but not limited to:
 - Research projects
 - Quizzes and tests
 - Critical thinking analyses

Full time teacher, St. James, Highwood, IL, February 2015 to June 2015

- Taught 5th through 7th grade math, 8th grade pre-algebra and 8th grade algebra in the mornings and two science classes in the afternoons.
- Former teacher found a new job (as a result of St. James closing), and I was hired to finish the year.

Leadership & Volunteer Activities

NEIU Elementary Education (ELED) and Middle Level Education (MLED) representative at NCATE conference, NEIU, Chicago, IL, November of 2012.

- On November 5, 2012, I was invited to represent the MLED and ELED majors, as well as the MSTQE minor, at the NCATE meeting held at NEIU.
- As a result, NCATE gave the University high marks in almost every category.

Kappa Delta Pi member, NEIU, Chicago, IL, fall of 2013.

- In the fall of 2013, I was invited to join Kappa Delta Pi, a prestigious organization recognizing students for their commitment to the field of education and exceptional grades and leadership qualities.

Additional Employment History

University Technology Services Student Worker, Northeastern Illinois University, Chicago, IL, August of 2011 to August of 2014.

Server and Manager, Porretta's Elegant Banquets, Chicago, IL, August of 2007 to April of 2011.

Skills

- Computer: Proficient in Microsoft Office, Google services (i.e. Google suite.) and diagnosing & repairing issues regarding software and hardware.
- Able to work on multiple operating systems, i.e. Windows, Mac OSX and Chrome OS.

References provided upon request